Rollin M. Pease papers, 1862-1960 (bulk, 1902-1953)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Rollin M. Pease papers, 1862-1960 (bulk, 1902-1953)
AZ 056
Pease, Rollin Malbone, 1879-1959
Contains chiefly scrapbooks and correspondence relating to the career of Rollin M. Pease. Includes programs, clippings, rollbooks, musical scores, correspondence, photographs and related biographical material, including many items pertaining to tenure at the University of Arizona School of Music, and his participation in Tucson, Ariz. community and church affairs.
6 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Pease was a bass-baritone concert artist known especially for his performances of "Elijah." He was a professor of Music at University of Arizona from 1931 to 1951.
Scope and Content Note
Contains chiefly scrapbooks and correspondence relating to the career of Rollin M. Pease.
Access Terms
Pease family -- Genealogy
University of Arizona -- Faculty
University of Arizona -- Students
University of Arizona. School of Music
Trinity Presbyterian Church (Tucson, Az.)
Music -- Programs
Correspondence
Scrapbooks
Musical Scores
Programs
Container List
- Scrapbook: Rollin Pease. 1902-1910 (Volume 1)
- Scrapbook: St. Paul. 1916-1917 (Volume 2)
- Scrapbook: Programs. 1917-1918 (Volume 3)
- Scrapbook: Programs. 1919-1922 (Volume 4)
- Scrapbook: Programs. 1923-1928 (Volume 5)
- Scrapbook: Programs. 1929-1936 (Volume 6)
- Scrapbook: Programs. 1936-1938 (Volume 7)
- Scrapbook: Programs. 1939-1940 (Volume 8)
- Scrapbook: Programs. 1941-1942 (Volume 9)
- Scrapbook: Programs. 1943-1945 (Volume 10)
- Scrapbook: Programs. 1946-1949 (Volume 11)
- Scrapbook: Festivals and Contests. 1919-1936 (Volume 12)
- Scrapbook: Trinity/Albany Park/Winona. No Date (Volume 13)
- Scrapbook: University of Arizona. 1931-1936 (Volume 14)
- Scrapbook: University of Arizona Roll Book. 1940-1953 (Volume 15)
- Scrapbook: The Pease genealogy. 1956 (Volume 16)
- Scrapbook: Rollin Pease. 1911-1914 (Volume 17)
- Scrapbook: Letters and outlines. 1924-1936 (Volume 18)
- Scrapbook: Letters A-L. 1920-1952 (Volume 19)
- Scrapbook: Letters M-Z. 1920-1952 (Volume 20)
- Scrapbook: University of Arizona Voice Roll Book. 1931-1941 (Volume 21)
- Scrapbook: Clippings and photographs. circa. 1927-1952 (Volume 22)
- Biographical materials. No Date (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Compositions, words for music. No Date (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Compositions, scores and parts. No Date (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Correspondence with parents. 1899-1916 (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
- Correspondence with Lena and children. 1900-1914 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with siblings. 1893-1926 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Correspondence with O.A. Pease and Burge McFall. 1894-1936 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- General correspondence. 1899-1912 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- General correspondence. 1912-1960 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
- Correspondence with Phi Mu Alpha Sinfonia. 1928-1960 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Notebook: Trinity Choir. 1955 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Pocket calendars. 1909-1912 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Speeches. No Date (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Source materials. No Date (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous music and programs. circa. 1868-1957 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Typescript, with handwritten additions: "America, an operatic drama and poem," by Lewis Adam Pease. 1891 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Photographs: R.M. Pease. No Date (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Photographs: Testimonial dinner. February 13, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Photographs: Groups. No Date (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Photographs: Miscellaneous. No Date (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Photographs: Family. No Date (Box 25, Folder 5)